The journey continues.
The Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers is a adventure,
fantasy, action film directed by Peter Jackson.
Frodo Baggins and the other members of the Fellowship continue on their
sacred quest to destroy the One Ring--but on separate paths.
Their destinies lie at two towers--Orthanc Tower in Isengard, where the corrupt wizard Saruman
awaits, and Sauron's fortress at Barad-dur, deep within the dark lands of Mordor.
Frodo and Sam are trekking to Mordor to destroy the One Ring of Power while Gimli,
Legolas and Aragorn search for the orc-captured Merry and Pippin.
All along, nefarious wizard Saruman awaits the Fellowship
members at the Orthanc Tower in Isengard.
Frodo, played by Elijah Wood.
Gandalf, played by Ian McKellen.
Aragorn, played by Viggo Mortensen.
Sam, played by Sean Astin.
Gollum, played by Andy Serkis.
Gimli / Treebeard (voice), played by John Rhys-Davies.
The Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers is a 2002 epic high fantasy adventure film directed by Peter Jackson from a screenplay by Fran Walsh, Philippa
Boyens, Stephen Sinclair, and Jackson, based on 1954's The Two Towers, the second volume of the novel The Lord of the Rings by J.
The sequel to 2001's The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring, the
film is the second instalment in The Lord of the Rings trilogy.
It features an ensemble cast including Elijah Wood, Ian McKellen, Liv Tyler, Viggo Mortensen, Sean Astin, Cate Blanchett, John Rhys-Davies, Bernard Hill,
Christopher Lee, Billy Boyd, Dominic Monaghan, Orlando Bloom, Hugo Weaving, Miranda Otto, David Wenham, Brad Dourif, Karl Urban, and Andy Serkis.
Continuing the plot of the previous film, it intercuts three storylines: Frodo and Sam continue their journey
toward Mordor to destroy the One Ring, now allied with Gollum, the ring's untrustworthy former bearer.
Merry and Pippin escape their orc captors, meet Treebeard the Ent, and help to plan an attack
on Isengard, the fortress of Sauron's vassal, the treacherous wizard Saruman.
Aragorn, Legolas, and Gimli come to the war-torn nation of Rohan and are reunited with the resurrected
Gandalf, before joining king Théoden to fight Saruman's army at the Battle of Helm's Deep.
The Two Towers was financed and distributed by American studio New Line Cinema, but filmed and edited
entirely in Jackson's native New Zealand, concurrently with the other two parts of the trilogy.
It premiered on 5 December 2002 at the Ziegfeld Theatre in New York City and was then
released on 18 December in the United States and on 19 December in New Zealand.
The film was acclaimed by critics and audiences, who considered it a landmark in filmmaking and an achievement in the fantasy film genre,
with praise for the visual effects (particularly Gollum), performances, action sequences, direction, and musical score.
It grossed $923 million worldwide during its original theatrical run, making it the highest-grossing film of 2002 and, at the time of
its release, the third-highest-grossing film of all time behind Titanic and Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone.
Following subsequent re-releases, it has grossed $942 million.
Like the other films in the trilogy, The Two Towers is widely recognised as one of the greatest and most
influential films ever made as well as one of the greatest sequels in cinema history.
The film received numerous accolades; at the 75th Academy Awards, it was nominated for six awards,
including Best Picture, winning for Best Sound Editing and Best Visual Effects.
The final instalment of the trilogy, The Return of
the King, was released in 2003.
The film explores themes of mission, army, based on novel or book, elves, dwarf.
The tone is uplifting and dark and thought_provoking.